Akshay Kumar Singh

Full Stack Developer with over 4 years of experience writing robust codebases for high volume businesses and passion for learning and creating more. Loves working on **Javascript** technologies such as **React.js**, **Node.js**, **Express** but believes in language agnosticism for software developers.



mail.akshayks@gmail.com



7417536894



linkedin.com/in/akshay240



github.com/akshaynox

SKILLS & COMPETENCES

Javascript

React JS

Node JS

Typescript

Express JS

Socket.io

Redux

Electron JS

Next.js

Tailwind CSS

Embedded JS

Shadon UI

Git Version Control

LESS/SASS

Materialize CSS

IBM Watson Assistant

NoSQL

Cloudant DB

MongoDB

Redis

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Credera

02/2023 - Present Bengaluru

Worked on **UI development** of the core product of a major American health insurance company, **Humana** and **Capella University** via **Adobe Experience Manager (AEM)**, as well as frontend development for the **Mercedez-Benz NFT collection** offering. Worked on an internal tool for **content testing** for production builds of AEM websites

Software Development Engineer

yellow.ai

01/2022 - 01/2023

Worked as an engineer in the **Product Led Growth** (PLG) team at yellow.ai to create a more self-serve product rather than being dependent of sales team to acquire customers.

Benaaluru

Software Engineer

HCL Technologies

06/2018 - 01/2022 Noida

Worked on several full-stack projects under the **HCL Dryice** banner and delivered them as premier products including smart runbook automation, an Al-enabled chatbot for enterprise, native desktop application development and **SoftBank's Pepper** robot which was showcased in the World Economic Forum, 2020 at Davos, Switzerland.

PROJECTS

yellow.ai (01/2022 - 01/2023) 🗹

- yellow.ai is the leading conversational CX automation platform to create bots for various business needs.
- Worked as a full-stack engineer in Product Led Growth team to create a more self-serve product and monitor product usage. Created various product improvements including a free trial system to attract and retain customers as well as various related product revamps.
- Technologies used: React, Node.js, Typescript, Redux, Ant design, Express.

DRYiCE Lucy (07/2019 - 01/2022)

- Lucy is an A.I. enabled **cognitive virtual assistant** powered by **IBM Watson**.
- Helped in automation of various helpdesk, FAQ and general third party API in the chatbot for enterprise customers.
- Technologies used: Node.js, Express.js, IBM Watson Assistant, Cloudant DB.

DRYiCE Lucy Gateway client (08/2020 - 01/2022)

- The Lucy Gateway Client is a desktop application made using Electron.js and connects to Lucy via websocket connection and relays requests from Lucy chatbot to tenant VMs which reside in customer environment.
- Enabled customers to rely less on manual configuration of Microsoft SCCM and automated all the administrative tasks.
- Technologies used: Electron.js, Socket.io.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology (Computer Science & Engineering)

Ajay Kumar Garg Engineering College, Ghaziabad (Dr. A.P.J. Abdul Kalam Technical University)

08/2014 - 06/2018

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi

Native or Bilingual